The spirits...
If only I could see them too.
A spirit?
Gadiel.
Yes?
We cannot form pacts with spirits.
It's been a long-standing
mystery of the royal family.
And since we are unable
to receive their blessings,
we have no choice but to rely
on the Vankreift family.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Everything's fine.
It looks like Ellen safely made
it back to the spirit castle.
I'm so glad.
Nevertheless, she'll be getting
an earful once we get home.
FEUD BETWEEN THE ROYAL FAMILY AND THE SPIRITS
Ori, would you mind hanging back a bit?
All right.
I saw your daughter wasn't in attendance.
My apologies. She isn't feeling very well.
No need to lie to my face.
It's a shame. I was hoping
to introduce my sons.
Oh, and...
Things have gotten quite
interesting with the bride.
Indeed. Sauvel is one lucky man,
to be able to marry a woman
as wonderful as her.
Well, I'm glad.
I shall await you and your daughter
at my castle a week from now.
I will allow you to meet my sons.
Now then, if you'll excuse me...
P-Please wait!
Just let me through!
Brother dearest...
You there, leave us.
What?
I'm here, so it'll be all right.
Explain yourself!
Dear, you mustn't be violent.
You look like you haven't the slightest clue.
Because of you, the royal family's
set their sights on Ellen!
Because of me?
That's right. You've been
condemned by Goddess Vár.
Not only that, the royal family knows!
Do you realize the terrible position
this puts the Vankreift family in?!
That's enough, dear.
I understand your rage is because
you love me and Ellen so much.
But...
We just got unlucky this time.
Meanwhile, it seems that blackhearted man
has frustratingly good luck.
What will Ellen say?
Goodness, she'll be fine.
She's our child, after all.
I'm certain she'll find a way
to surprise everyone.
Just like she did here, no?
Now, Aria... do you have the courage
to offer up your daughter
for a crime someone else committed?
What?
Would you be able to sacrifice your
flesh and blood for someone else?
S-Sacrifice Rafilia? How could I?!
Right? I knew you'd understand.
In exchange for keeping quiet
about your condemnation,
the royal family has demanded
our precious daughter, Ellen.
What is this all about?
Aria, you pledged a false oath before the
goddess on your marriage papers, didn't you?
A false oath?
When you signed them, you were thinking
of someone other than Sauvel, weren't you?
That thorny bruise on your wrist
is Goddess Vár's condemnation.
What?! C-Condemnation?
It's proof of the sin of swearing
a false oath before the goddess.
Sin?
Do you not love my brother?
Were just you toying with him?!
N-No!
Don't play dumb with me!
Wait, dear.
The bruise is still faint.
This probably means she does love Sauvel.
Then what's the meaning of this?
Aria, I think you know.
This is a warning from Big Sister Vár.
Do not let your eyes wander.
Wholeheartedly love Sauvel.
If you proceed as you have been,
it is down the path to ruin.
What?
There. Now no one else will
be able see your bruise.
However, it is visible to you.
It will only disappear once
you love Sauvel with all your heart.
Listen well. You are to tell
no one of this. Not even Sauvel.
With Agiel gone, I thought that
Uncle Sauvel could finally be happy...
I think this is the first time I've
ever seen my father so angry.
But a declaration of war, eh,
Mr. Blackheart?
Very well!
In that case, it's time I learned
about our enemy!
Father.
Why is it that the royal family
cannot form a pact with the spirits?
Not only can we not form pacts,
we cannot even approach them.
The reason for this remains
a long-standing mystery.
However...
What should I do?
They told me not to tell Sauvel, but...
Still, there's what my sister-in-law said.
If I'm to love Sauvel with all my heart...
C-Coming! I'll be right there.
Are you all right, Aria?
Yes. I'm sorry for keeping everyone waiting.
No worries. Besides that, how are you feeling?
You don't look well.
Are you all right?
Yes, I'm fine now.
But may I stay here for just a little longer?
Of course you may.
Sauvel.
Milady, if you make too much of a mess,
your mother and father will scold you.
It'll be fine, Vint.
I'm collecting intel on our enemy.
They wouldn't get angry about this.
No, I won't let them get angry!
If there is anything you'd like
to know, you need but ask.
I believe you'll find what
you're looking for sooner that way.
Then do you know anything about the
curse the spirits placed on the royal family?
How do you know about that, milady?
I saw a black mist
coming off the royal family.
And when I asked my mother,
she said it was a curse by the spirits.
Goodness. You can already see that?
Mother said the same thing.
Still, I don't know much about it,
and I feel it's yet too soon for you, milady.
We're past that. I told you,
I'm collecting intelligence on our enemy.
What do you mean by "our enemy"?
Mr. Blackheart... Oh, I mean, King Ravisel.
He has leverage on the Vankreift family
and is using it to summon me and my
father to the castle against our will.
Those unrepentant bastards!
They would again dare to...
Vint!
Milady, my apolo—
So you do know something?
I absolutely have to find out.
Understood. I shall tell you.
It all happened... two hundred years
ago during the Monster Tempest.
The measures taken by the king at the
time to fight the tempest
are what begot the curse.
What in the world did he do?
The royal family demanded the spirit queen
come out to turn the tides of battle.
Naturally, we couldn't
just give into his demand.
Our queen would never lend her powers
to humans for something like that.
However, the fed-up king decided
he'd resort to a forbidden act.
A forbidden act?
Ellen, I'm coming in!
We're home, Ellen.
It's gotten very late.
I'm not angry at you for breaking
our promise, so come here.
What's the matter, Ellen?
Mother, Vint told me everything.
Oh? About what?
The royal family's curse.
I see. So you asked him, did you?
You're a kind child.
I haven't told you because I thought
you might try to break the curse.
But we spirits will never
forgive the royal family.
The tragedy and the cries of our kin...
Please understand.
I am not so kind.
In fact, I find the royal family impudent
for continuing to live so comfortably,
oblivious to the cause of the curse.
Ellen, dear...
I'm sorry.
Why are you apologizing, Father?
I have human blood as well.
And Grammie, Pawpaw,
Uncle Sauvel, Uncle Alberto...
I love everyone from the
Vankreift family too!
Besides, I am your daughter.
I am the daughter of both of you.
And I'm proud of that. There's no reason
for you to worry, Father.
What cannot be allowed to stand
is the royal family
still trying to use the spirits' power
while unaware of the gravity of their sin.
That's my girl!
I don't want to hear that, Father.
Why not?!
You were watching, weren't you, Ellen?
Yes. You mean Mr. Blackheart's
declaration of war, right?
I say bring on the challenge!
You certainly are Rovel's child!
Mother, I don't want to hear that!
Again, why not?!
I think my daughter's in her rebellious phase.
By the way, what happened afterward?
That Aria... She went
and told Sauvel of her sin.
What?
After Rovel told her not to and everything.
What a foolish girl, don't you think?
And so, Sauvel ended up calling off
the reception party midway.
My, the house was in quite an uproar.
I was so furious that I told him I
won't be coming home for a while.
Mother and Roren did want to see you, but...
I see. Poor Uncle Sauvel.
Yeah.
Father, would it be all right
if I go visit Grammie
and the others when Aunt Aria isn't there?
Yes, but I just declared
I wouldn't be returning,
so it's a little hard to visit after that.
I want to see Grammie and Pawpaw
and Uncle Sauvel and Uncle Alberto!
I really want to see them!
Let's go! Let's go tomorrow!
Well, that's really sudden.
Yes. It's urgent.
You could have just gone
directly into the mansion.
I told you, this is kind of hard for me.
Grammie!
Oh, my sweet Ellen, I was so lonely!
Lady Isabella, you're
suffocating the young lady.
My! I'm very sorry, Ellen, dear.
I was just so happy to see you.
Grammie...
It has been too long, Lady Ellen.
Pawpaw, I missed you!
My, just when I thought things were looking
brighter for the house... This again.
It's all right.
Don't cry!
I'm sorry.
Don't misunderstand.
I'm happy just to have you here, Ellen.
Grammie...
Did you need something?
Uncle Sauvel!
Nice to meet you, Aunt Aria.
I am Rovel's daughter, Ellen.
Greet her back.
Brother, was there something
you needed to say to Aria?
I don't. Ellen does.
What did you want to talk about?
Well, it's not really a talk.
It's a warning.
What?
Ellen is Rafilia's age, but as you
can see, she's no ordinary child.
Take what she says seriously.
Understood.
My mother was mindful
of Uncle Sauvel's feelings
and cast a spell so that only
you could see the proof of your sin.
Yet you disobeyed my father's order not
to tell anyone and revealed this to my uncle.
Th-That was because...
Your mother told me to love Sauvel, so...
Should I really be keeping secrets
from the one I love?
Did you think Uncle Sauvel would
forgive you if you told him?
Who would forgive someone for confessing that
they thought of someone else at the altar?
It's an insult to the Vankreift family.
That's right.
Sauvel told you about Agiel,
yet you're doing the same thing.
That's not true!
I'm going to be part of the family!
So it's only natural to seek
my new brother's favor!
You already acknowledged that
your feelings are impure.
That is why Big Sister Vár condemned you.
And the king knows it.
I'm sorry.
No, it's not your fault, Uncle Sauvel.
Aunt Aria, the Vankreift family,
beloved by the spirits,
is indispensable to the royal family.
Even I know that. That's only obvious
with my brother dearest the hero here.
It's more than that!
The reason the royal family dogs us so
isn't because of my father's title.
Above all else, they need his power.
His power is so great that it
keeps neighboring nations in check.
However, your selfish actions risk
stripping our kingdom of its power.
I don't understand at all.
What are you talking about?
Because of you, my father declared
he wouldn't return here for fear
of straining your relationship
with Uncle Sauvel.
And what of it?
If my father, a key part
of our military might,
were to disappear from the human world...
Get to the point!
Perhaps the royal family will see it this way:
"If the nuisance were gone,
the hero may return."
"Getting rid of the nuisance
will fix everything."
The... nuisance?
I'm talking about you, Aunt Aria!
Me?
Why do you think the royal family
attended Uncle's wedding after
what happened with Agiel?
It was to assess your worth.
That can't be...
Not only to see whether you are
worthy of the Vankreift family,
but also to determine your importance
and value as a person.
And yet you've done nothing but drag us down!
No... No!
Aria, there are many women who fall
in love with Rovel at first sight.
It may have been inevitable
that you were one of them.
Still, Sauvel was so happy
to finally be able to marry you.
I do love Sauvel!
Then cease your impure feelings for my father
that only put your life at risk.
Listen carefully, Aunt Aria.
If you dare pursue my father,
my mother and I will show no mercy.
We will slowly and certainly crush you.
You've been warned!
Despite everything, I...
I want to believe in Aria.
I'm sorry for forcing an eight-year-old
to say such things.
No, I was the one who
couldn't bear to keep silent.
I'm sorry for acting out of line.
If it weren't for you, Ellen,
I think this family would've fallen apart.
Truly, thank you.
Uncle...
Now then, we should be off to the castle,
shouldn't we, Father?
Yeah, you're right. Man, I don't wanna...
If that's the case,
you need a new dress, Ellen!
Rovel, we need something for you too!
Roren, immediately call in
our best seamstress!
Yes, milady! I'll make
the arrangements right away.
Things are going to get busy!
I'm sorry. My mother always wanted a daughter.
That's why she goes so overboard.
I see. In that case...
Makeup artists assemble!
I think you should share
this fate with me, Uncle Sauvel.
Wha...?!
If you don't want to get dragged into this,
Father, please restrain Uncle Sauvel.
You got it, Ellen.
What?!
Forgive me, Sauvel!
B-Brother?!
I cannot argue with my daughter.
Uncle Sauvel!
Prepare yourself!
Hmm, h-how does it look?
You look wonderful without a beard, Uncle!
Yeah.
I thought if we make him look cool, maybe
Aunt Aria won't have eyes for anyone else.
And that's why you wanted to see Sauvel?
I see. What a great idea!
TRANSLATION: YUKARI MURASE-LOUDEN
EDITING: RILEY DALTON
QUALITY CHECK: ASHLEY BARBOZA
TRANSLATION CHECK: ELIZABETH ELLIS